>> A resource group is a unit
of management for your
resources in Azure.
You can think of
your resource group as
a container that allows
you to aggregate and
manage all the resources required for
your application into
a single manageable units.
This allows you to
manage the application
collectively over its life cycle,
rather than manage
components individually.
You can manage and
apply to following at
the resource group level:
metering and billing,
policies, monitoring and alerts,
quotas, and access control.
When you delete a resource group,
you delete all the
resources within it.
When creating and placing
resources within resource groups,
there are a few considerations
to take into account.
Each Azure resource must exist in
one and only one resource group.
A resource group can contain resorts
that reside in different regions.
You can add or remove a resource
to a resource group at anytime.
You can move a resource from
one resource group to another.
Resources for an application do not
need to exist in
the same resource group,
however, it is recommended
that you keep them
in the same resource group
for ease of management.