>> Serverless computing is
a Cloud hosted execution environment
that runs your code,
but obstructs the underlying
hosting environment.
You create an instance of the
service and you add your code.
No infrastructure configuration or
maintenance is required
or even allowed.
You configure your serverless app
to respond to events.
An event could be a REST endpoint,
a Periodic Timer, or
even a message received
from another Azure service.
The serverless app runs only
when it's triggered by an event.
Scaling and performance
are handled automatically
and you're billed only for
the exact resources you use.
You don't even need
to reserve resources.
Some of the most common
serverless service types
in Azure are Azure Functions.
Azure Functions are ideal when
you're only concerned with the code
running your service and
not the underlying platform
or infrastructure.
Azure Functions are commonly used
when you need to perform
work in response to
an event and when that work can be
completed quickly
within seconds or less.
Azure Functions scale
automatically and charges
accrue only when
a function is triggered.
So, there are solid choice
when demand is
variable. Azure Logic Apps.
Azure Logic Apps is a Cloud
service that helps you
automate and orchestrate
tasks, business processes,
and workflows, when you need
to integrate apps, data,
systems, and services across
enterprises and organizations.
Logic Apps simplifies how you design
and build scalable solutions,
whether in the Cloud,
on-premises, or both.
Azure Event Grid.
Azure Event Grid allows
you to easily build
applications with
event-based architectures.
It's a fully managed intelligent
event routing service that
uses a publish-subscribe model
for uniform event consumption.
Event Grid has built-in support for
events coming from Azure services,
such as storage blobs
and resource groups.