>> Availability sets are a way
for you to ensure
your application remains
online if a high-impact
maintenance event
is required or
a hardware failure occurs.
Availability sets are made up of
update domains and fault domains.
When a maintenance event occurs,
such as a performance update or
a critical security patch
applied to a host,
the update is sequenced
through update domains.
Sequencing updates using
update domains ensures that
the entire datacenter is not
unavailable during
platform updates and patching.
Update domains are
a logical section of
the datacenter and they are
implemented with software and logic.
Fault domains provide for
the physical separation of
your workload across different
hardware in the datacenter.
This includes power, cooling,
network hardware that supports
the physical servers
located in the server rack.
In the event that
the hardware supporting
the server rack becomes unavailable,
only that rack of servers will
be affected by the outage.