>> Compliance Manager is
a workflow-based risk
assessment in the Trust Portal,
that enables you to track, assign,
and verify your organization's
regulatory compliance
activities related to
Microsoft Professional Services and
Microsoft Cloud Services
such as Office 365,
Dynamics 365, and Azure.
Compliance Manager provides
the following features.
It combines the
following three items,
detailed information
provided by Microsoft
to auditors and regulators as part of
various third-party audits of
Microsoft's Cloud Services
against various standards.
Information that Microsoft compiles
internally for its
compliance with regulations.
An organization's self-assessment of
their own compliance with
these standards and regulations.
It also enables you to assign, track,
and record compliance on
assessment-related activities,
which can help
your organization across
team buyers to achieve your
organization's compliance goals.
Provides a Compliance Score to
help you track your progress and
prioritize auditing controls that'll
help you reduce your
organization's exposure to risk.
Provides a secure repository
in which to upload and manage
evidence and other artifacts
related to compliance activities.
Produces richly detailed reports
in Microsoft Excel that
documents the compliance activities
performed by Microsoft
in your organization,
which can be provided to auditors,
regulators, and other
compliance stakeholders.
Note, Compliance Manager is
a dashboard that provides
a summary of your data protection
and compliance structure,
and recommendations to improve
data protection and compliance.
The customer actions provided in
Compliance Manager are
recommendations only.
It is up to each organization to
evaluate the effectiveness of
these recommendations in
their respective regulatory
environments prior to implementation.
Recommendations found in
Compliance Manager should not be
interpreted as a guarantee
of compliance.