>> In this module, you've
learned about Cloud computing,
what it is, a moderate
key characteristics.
You've learned what are
some of the key terms
and concepts of Cloud computing,
such as high availability,
agility, elasticity,
global reach, capital expenditure
versus operational expenditure in
the context of Cloud computing,
economies of scale, and
the consumption-based cost model.
You then learned about
the public Cloud,
the Private cloud, and
the Hybrid cloud models.
You learned what of the key
characteristics of each model,
and also what are the considerations
you need to take account
of when using them,
as well as how they compare
and when they might be used.
Finally, you learned about
the different types of
Cloud services available;
infrastructure as a service,
platform as a service,
and software as a service.
You learned about the key
characteristics of each service,
what are the
considerations you need to
take account of when using them,
how they compare, and
when they might be used.
You also learned about the different
management responsibilities
onto each service type.