>> Trust Center is
a website resource containing
information and details about how
Microsoft implements
and supports security,
privacy, compliance, and transparency
in all our cloud products
and services.
The Trust Center is an important part
of the Microsoft
Trusted Cloud Initiative,
and provide support and resources
for the legal and
compliance community.
The Trust Center site provides:
In-depth information
about security, privacy,
compliance offerings,
policies, features,
and practices across
our cloud products.
Recommended resources in
the form of a curated list of
the most applicable and widely
used resources for each topic.
Information specific to
key organizational roles,
including business managers,
tenant admins or data security teams,
risk assessment and privacy offers,
and legal compliance teams.
Direct guidance and support for
when you can't find what
you're looking for.
The Service Trust Portal hosts
the Compliance Manager Service,
and is the Microsoft public site for
publishing audit reports on order
compliance-related information
related to Microsoft's
cloud services.
STP users can download audit reports
produced by external auditors
and gain insight from
Microsoft-authored reports
that provide details on how
Microsoft builds and
operates its cloud services.
STP is a companion feature
to the Trust Center,
and allows you to:
Access audit reports
across Microsoft Cloud services
on a single page.
Access compliance guides to help
you understand how you can use
Microsoft cloud services features
to manage compliance with
various regulations.
Access trust documents to
help you understand how
Microsoft cloud services
help protect your data.
To access some STP materials,
you must sign in as
an authenticated user with your
Microsoft cloud services account.
Either an Azure AD organization
account or a Microsoft account.
Then review and accept the
Microsoft Non-Disclosure Agreement
for Compliance Materials.
Existing customers can access
the STP at the site, aka.ms/STP.