>> Azure Database Services
are fully managed
PaaS database services that free up
valuable time you'd otherwise
spend managing your database.
Enterprise grade performance with
built-in high availability
means you can
scale quickly and reach
global distribution without
worrying about costly downtime.
Developers can take advantage of
industry leading innovations such
as built-in security with
automatic monitoring
and threat detection.
Automatic tuning for
improved performance
on turnkey global distribution.
Some of the most common data
service types in Azure are;
Azure Cosmos DB:
Microsoft Azure Cosmos DB
is a globally distributed
database service that
enables you to elastically
and independently scale
throughput and storage across
any number of Azure's
geographic regions.
You can use Cosmos DB to store data
that is updated and maintained
by users around the world.
It makes it easy to
build scalable highly
responsive applications
at global scale.
Azure SQL Database: Azure SQL
Database is a relational database as
a service based on
the latest stable version of
Microsoft SQL Server database engine.
SQL database is
a high-performance, reliable,
fully managed and secure
database that you can
use to build data driven
applications and websites in
the programming language of
your choice without needing
to manage infrastructure.
Azure Database Migration:
The Azure Database Migration Service
is a fully managed
service designed to
enable seamless migrations from
multiple database sources to
Azure data platforms
with minimal downtime.