>> A public cloud is owned and
operated by a cloud service provider.
They provide resources
and services to
multiple organizations
and users which
connect to the Cloud service via
secure narrow connection,
typically over the internet.
Public cloud characteristics
would include;
resources such as storage,
processing, power, et cetera,
do not belong to the organisation
or users that is using the resource,
rather they are owned and operated
by the cloud service provider.
The Cloud service provider is
entirely responsible
for the purchase,
maintenance, and management
of the Cloud hardware.
Resources would be made available to
multiple organizations and end-users.
Typically, it's connected to security
over the internet
using a web browser.
It is accessible to the public.
It does not require
deep tech knowledge
to start using public cloud.
A private cloud is
owned and operated by
the organization that uses
the resources from the cloud.
An organization that creates
a private cloud in
it's own data center,
it's completely responsible for
the operation of
the services they provide.
Private cloud characteristics
would include;
the owner and user of
the cloud services are the same,
the owner is entirely
responsible for the purchase,
maintenance, and management
of the Cloud hardware.
A private cloud operates only within
mono organization and resources are
typically used by
a single business or organization.
An action to it is typically by
a private network and
is highly secure.
It is not accessible to the public.
It requires deep technical
knowledge to setup,
manage, and maintain a private cloud.
A Hybrid Cloud combines the use of
both public and private
clouds allowing
you to run your application in
the most appropriate location.
Hybrid cloud characteristics
include; ownership is split.
The cloud provider being responsible
for the public cloud resources
and private cloud organization
responsibly for the operation
of the private cloud.
Specific resources are
run in are used in
a public cloud and other resources
are run in are used
in a private cloud.
Allows an organization to leverage
some of the benefits of cost,
efficiency, and scale available
with a public cloud model.
Retains and management control
that comes at a private cloud model.
Technical skills are still required
to maintain your private cloud
and ensure both cloud models
can inter-operate successfully.