>> A geography is a discrete market
typically containing
two or more regions,
that preserves data residency
and compliance boundaries.
Geographies allow customers with
specific data residency and
compliance needs to keep
their data and applications close.
Geographies ensured
a data residency, sovereignty,
compliance, and
resiliency requirements
are honored within
geographical boundaries.
Geographies are fault tolerant to
withstand complete
regional failure to
the connection to our dedicated,
high-capacity networking
infrastructure.
Geographies are broken
up into Americas,
Europe, Asia Pacific,
Middle East, and Africa.