>> You can configure and manage Azure
using a broad range of
tools and platforms.
There are tools available
for the command-line,
language specific software
development kits,
or SDKs, developer tools,
tools for migration, and many others.
Some of them are common tools
that can be relevant for
day-to-day managing and
interaction include, Azure Portal.
Azure Portal is a website accessed
via a web browser and going
to the URL https://portal.azure.com.
From here, you can interact manually
with all the Azure Services.
You can identify a service
you're looking for,
obtain links for help and more,
learn particular topics, and
you can deploy and manage
and delete resources.
Azure PowerShell. Azure PowerShell
is a module that you add to
Windows PowerShell or PowerShell
core that enables you
to connect to your Azure
subscription and manage resources.
PowerShell provide services such as
the Shell window and
the command parsing.
An Azure PowerShell then adds
the Azure specific
commands. Azure CLI.
Azure CLI is a cross platform
command-line program that connects to
Azure and executes administrative
commands on Azure resources.
Cross-platform means that
it can be run on Windows,
Linux, or Mac OS. Azure Cloud Shell.
Azure Cloud Shell is a
browser-based scripting
environment in your portal.
It provides the
flexibility of choosing
the Shell experience that
best suits the way you work.
Linux users can opt
for a bash experience
while Windows users can
opt for PowerShell.