>> Cloud Computing is the delivery of
various computing services over
the internet to offer
faster innovation,
flexible resources, and
economies of scale,
you typically only pay for the
services that you consume.
Cloud Computing helps you
run your business more
efficiently and to scale
up and down as you need,
and grow as your business changes.
Cloud services is a big shift from
the traditional way businesses
think about IT resources.
Some of the main characteristics
include; high availability,
which is the ability to keep
services up and running for
long periods of time with very
little, if any, downtime.
Scalability. The ability to increase
our decrease resources
for any given workload.
Elasticity. The ability to
increase or decrease resources
as needed automatically.
Agility. The ability to react
quickly. Disaster recovery.
The ability to recover from an event
which is taken down
a product or a service.
Global reach. The ability to
reach audiences around the globe.
Security. Many
Cloud providers can provide
better security services than
you could otherwise achieve yourself.
There are two important factors
to consider when
considering the costs
of Cloud services.
Firstly, economies of scale.
The concept of economies of scale
is the ability to do things more
cheaply and efficiently by
operating at a large scale.
Cloud providers such
as Microsoft, Google,
and Amazon are working
on a huge scale,
and are able to leverage
the benefits of economies of
scale and pass those benefits
on that our customers.
Is it apparent to end
uses in a number of ways?
One of which is their ability
to acquire hardware more
cheaply than if a single user
or smaller business,
or purchasing it themselves.
Secondly, does capital expenditure
on operational expenditure.
Capital expenditure
is the spending of
money on physical
infrastructure upfront.
That's how new businesses would
have traditionally operated.
Operational expenditure is
the spending of money on
services or products and being
billed for them as you use them.
Getting access to money up front
can be a severe limiting factor for
businesses and prevent
new companies or
new services and products
ever getting off the ground.
The fact that you can
start up a new service
and pay only for what you use with
no need for big upfront capital costs
has dramatically changed
the business landscape,
and allows new companies to get up
and running relatively quickly.
Cloud services operate on
a consumption-based model,
which means that users only pay
for the resources that they use.