>> The following best
practice guidelines can
help minimize your Azure costs.
Perform cost analysis.
Plan your Azure solution wisely.
Carefully consider the products,
services, and resources you need,
and read the relevant
documentation to
understand how each of your choices
are metered and billed.
Additionally, you should calculate
your projected costs by using
the Azure pricing and Total Cost
of Ownership calculators,
only adding the products, services,
and resources you need.
Monitor usage with Azure Advisor.
In an efficient architecture,
provision resources much to
demand for those resources.
Azure Advisor is a feature that
identifies unused or
underutilized resources.
Enable Azure Advisor to implement
its recommendations by
removing unused resources and
configuring your resources
to match demand.
Your spending limits.
Free trial customers on
some credit-based Azure subscriptions
can use spending limits,
which Azure provides to help
prevent you from exhausting
the credit on your account
within each billing period.
If you have a credit
base subscription
and you reach your
configured spending limit,
Azure suspends your subscription
until a new billing period begins.
A spending limit feature is not
available for customers who aren't
using credit by subscriptions,
such as pay-as-you-go subscribers.
Use Azure reservations.
Azure reservations
offer discounted prices
on certain Azure products
and resources.
To get a discount, you reserved
products and resources
by paying in advance.
You can pre-pay for one year or
three years of use
of virtual machines,
SQL database compute capacity,
Azure Cosmos database throughput,
and other Azure resources.
Azure reservations
are only available to
Enterprise, or CSP customers,
and for Pay-as-You-Go subscriptions.
Choose low cost locations in regions.
The cost of Azure products, services,
and resources can vary
across locations,
regions, and if possible,
you should use them
in those locations
and regions where they cost less.
Research available
cost-saving offers.
Keep up to date with
the latest Azure customer
and subscription offers,
and switch to the offers that
provide the greatest
cost-saving benefit.
Apply tags to identify cost owners.
Tags help you manage
costs associated with
the different groups of
Azure products and resources.
You can apply tags to groups of
Azure products and resources
to organize billing data.
For example, if you run
several virtual machines
for different teams,
you can use tags to categorize
costs by department,
such as human resources,
marketing, or finance.
Tags make it easy to identify
groups that generate
the biggest Azure costs,
so you can adjust
your spending accordingly.
Azure Cost Management.
Cost Management is an Azure product
that provides a set of
tools for monitoring,
allocating, and optimizing
your Azure costs.
The main features of
the Azure Cost Management tool
include Reporting,
Data enrichment,
Budgets,
Alerting,
Recommendations,
and Price.