>> Azure Compute is
an on-demand computing service
for running Cloud-based applications.
Provides computing
resources such as disks,
processors, memory, networking,
and operating systems.
The resources are
available on demand,
and can typically be made available
in minutes or even seconds.
You pay only for the resources you
use and only for as long
as you're using them.
There are two common service types
for performing compute in
Azure: virtual machines
and containers.
Let's look at virtual machines first.
So, what is the virtual machine?
Virtual machines or VMs
are software emulations
of physical computers.
They include a virtual processor,
memory storage, and
networking resources.
They host an operating system
and you're able to
install and run software just
like a physical computer.
Azure supports a wide range of
computing solutions including Linux,
Windows Server, Microsoft SQL Server,
Oracle, IBM and SAP.
Examples of some core
Azure Compute services for
virtual machines would be
Azure Virtual Machines.
Azure VMs lets you create and use
virtual machines in the Cloud,
provides infrastructure as a service
and can be used in a variety
of different ways.
When you need total control over
an operating system and environment,
Azure VMs are an ideal choice.
Just like a physical computer,
you're able to customize all of
the software running on the VM.
VM Scale Sets.
Virtual Machines Scale Sets are
an Azure Compute resource
that you can use to
deploy and manage a set
of identical VMs.
With all VMs configured the same,
VM Scale Sets are designed
to support true autoscale,
and makes it easier to
build large scale services
targeting big compute and big data.
As demand goes up, more
virtual machine instances
can be added and as
the demand goes down,
virtual machine instances
can be removed.
Now, let's look at
the second common service type when
dealing with Azure Compute,
namely containers.
So, what are containers?
Containers are a
virtualization environment.
However, unlike virtual machines,
they do not include
an operating system.
Instead, they reference
the operating system
of the host environment
that runs the container.
Containers are meant
to be lightweight
and are designed to be created,
scaled out, and stopped dynamically.
This allows you to respond
to changes on demand and
quickly restart in case of
a crash or hardware interruption.
Examples of some core
Azure Compute Services
for containers would be.
Azure Container Instances,
Azure Container Instances offers
the fastest and simplest way
to run a container in Azure
without having to manage
any virtual machines or adopt
any additional services.
It is a PaaS offering that allows
you to upload your containers,
which you're going to run for
you. Azure Kubernetes Service.
A task of automating and
managing a large number of
containers on how do you interact
is known as Orchestration.
Azure Kubernetes Service is
a complete orchestration
service for containers,
with distributed architectures
and large volumes of containers.