>> If you have an issue in Azure,
you can request assistance from
the Azure support team by
creating a new support ticket.
You can create a support
ticket by the Azure portal.
You can choose "Help and Support"
from the left navigation menu in
the portal and open
the "Help and Support
Blade" and select "View
support requests".
You can check the status and
details of your support request
in the Azure portal again from
the Help and Support Blade.
There are several additional
support channels that are
available inside of Azure
as official support plans.
Microsoft Developer Network Forums,
get support by reading responses
to Azure technical questions from
Microsoft's developers and testers on
the MSDN Azure discussion forums.
Stack Overflow: You
can view answers to
the questions from the development
community on Stack Overflow.
Server Fault: See
community responses to questions
about system and network administration
in Azure on Server Fault.
Azure feedback forums: Read ideas
and suggestions for improving
Azure made by Azure users and
customers on the Azure
feedback forums.
Twitter: Tweet @AzureSupport
to get answers
and support from the official
Microsoft Azure Twitter channel.
The Azure Knowledge Center is
a searchable database that contains
answers to common support questions,
from a community of Azure experts,
developers, customers and users.
You can browse through
all the answers
within the Azure Knowledge Center,
find specific solutions by entering
keywords search terms into
the text entry field,
and further refine your search
results by selecting products or
tags from the list provided
from the drop-down list.