>> Two fundamental concepts
that need to be
understood when talking
about identity and access,
are authentication and authorization.
They all depend everything
else that happens on a course
sequentially in on Identity
and access process.
Authentication is the process of
establishing the identity
of a person or service,
looking to access a resource.
It involves the act of challenging
a party for legitimate credentials,
and provides the basis for
creating a security principle,
for identity and access control use.
It establishes if they
are, who they say they're.
Authorization is the process
of establishing what level of
access and authenticated
person or service has,
it specifies what data
they're allowed to access and
what they can do with it.
Azure Active Directory, is
a Microsoft Cloud based Identity
and access management service.
Azure AD, helps employees
of an organization,
sign in and access
external and internal resources.
External resources might include;
Microsoft Office 365,
the Azure Portal,
an other SaaS applications.
Internal resources might include;
apps on your corporate
network and intranet,
along with any cloud apps developed
by your own organization.
Azure AD provide services such
as: Authentication is includes;
verified identity to access
applications and resources,
and providing functionality, such as;
Self-Service Password Reset and
Multifactor Authentication.
Single-Sign-On.
Single-Sign-On enables users
to remember only one ID and
one password to access
multiple applications.
Application management, manager cloud
and on-premises applications.
Business to business
identity services,
manage your guest users
and external partners
by maintaining control over
your own corporate data.
Business to customer
identity services,
customize and control
how users sign up,
sign-in and monitor profiles when
using your apps and services.
Device management,
manage how your cloud
or on-premises devices
access your corporate data.
Multifactor Authentication,
provides additional security for
your identities by acquiring
two or more elements for
full authentication.
These elements fall into three
categories: Something you know,
it could be a password or
the answer to security question.
Something you possess, might be
a mobile app that receives
a notification or
a token generating device,
and something you are, is
typically some sort of
bio-metric property,
such as, a fingerprint or face scan,
use on many mobile devices.
Using MFA increases identity security
by limiting the impact
of credential exposure.
To fully authenticate,
an attacker who has
a user's password would
also need to have
possession of their phone or
their fingerprint for example.
In this case, authentication
with only a single factor is
insufficient and the attacker will be
unable to use those credentials
to authenticate.
MFA should be enabled
wherever possible,
as MFA adds enormous
benefits to security.