>> Microsoft Azure is made up
of data centers located
around the globe.
These data centers are
organized and made
available to end users by region.
Region is a geographical area
on the planet containing
at least one or potentially
multiple data centers
that are in close
proximity and networked
together with a low-latency network.
For most Azure services,
when deploying a resource in Azure,
you choose in which region you
want to deploy your resource.
A few examples of
regions are, West US,
Canada Central, West Europe,
Australia East, or Japan West.
Azure has more global regions
than any of the cloud provider.
This provides customers
the flexibility and scale
needed to bring applications
closer to users around the world,
preserving data
residency and offering
comprehensive compliance and
resiliency options for customers.
At a time of this recording,
Azure is generally available in
42 regions around the globe,
with plans announced for
12 additional regions.
Each Azure region is paired
with another region but in
the same geography such
as US, Europe, or Asia.
This approach allows replication of
resources across the geography that
helps reduce the likelihood
of interruptions
due to events such as
natural disasters,
civil unrest, or power outages.
Examples of region pairs would
be West US paired with East US,
or South-East Asia
paired with East Asia.
Azure also has some special regions
that you might want to use
when building Azure applications
for compliance or legal purposes.
We'll discuss these more
later in the course,
but these special regions
include US government,
which are physical and logical
narrowed isolated instances
of Azure for the US government
agencies and the partners.
Azure Germany, made available
to a data trustee model,
whereby customer data
remains in Germany under
control of T-Systems at
Deutsche Telecom company,
acting as the German data trustee.
Any user or enterprise who needs
their data to reside in
Germany can use the service.
Azure China. Azure China is
available through
a unique partnership
between Microsoft and 21Vianet,
where Microsoft does not directly
maintain the data centers.