DevOps brings together people,
processes and technology,
automating software delivery to
provide continuous value to users.
Azure DevOps services
allow you to create,
build and release pipelines that
provide continuous integration,
delivery and deployment
for your applications.
You can integrate repositories
and application tests,
perform application monitoring,
and work with build artifacts.
You can also work with
backlog items for tracking,
automate infrastructure deployments,
and integrate a range of
third party tools and services
such as Jenkins and Chef.
All of these functions
and many more are
closely integrated with
Azure to allow for
consistent repeatable deployments for
your applications to provide
streamlined build and
release processes.
Some of the main DevOps services
available with Azure are:
Azure DevOps Services.
Azure DevOps Services,
formerly known as Visual
Studio Team Services or VSTS,
provides development
collaboration tools,
including high performance pipelines,
free private git repositories,
configurable Kanban boards, and
extensive automated and
cloud-based load testing.
Azure DevTestLabs.
Azure DevTestLabs is a service
that helps developers and testers
quickly create environments in Azure
while minimizing waste
and controlling costs.
Users can test their latest
application versions by
quickly provisioning
Windows and Linux environments using
reusable templates and artifacts.
You can easily integrate
your deployment pipeline with
DevTestLabs to provision
on-demand environments.