>> Azure Storage is a service
that you can use to store files,
messages, tables, and
other types of information.
You can use Azure Storage on its own,
for example, as a file share.
But developers also often use
it as a store for working data.
Such stores can be used
by websites, mobile apps,
desktop applications, and many
other types of custom solutions.
Azure Storage is also used by IaaS
virtual machines and
PaaS cloud services.
You can generally think of
Azure Storage in categories.
First, in the structured data.
Structured data adheres to a schema,
so all of the data has
the same fields or properties.
Structured data can be stored in
a database table with
rows and columns.
Secondly, semi-structured data.
Semi-structured data
is less organized than
structured data and is not
stored in a relational format,
meaning the fields do not need to fit
into tables, rows, and columns.
Semi-structured data
is also referred to as
non-relational or NoSQL data.
Thirdly, unstructured data.
Unstructured data encompasses data
that has no designated
structure to it.
This also means that there are
no restrictions in the kinds
of data it can hold.
For example, a blob can
hold a PDF document,
a JPEG image, a JSON file,
or video content.
As such, unstructured data
is becoming more prominent
as businesses try to tap
into new data sources.
Some of the most common
storage service types in
Azure are: Blob Storage.
Azure Blob Storage is unstructured,
meaning that there are no
restrictions in the data it can hold.
Blobs are highly scalable
an absorber blobs in
much the same way as
they would work with files on
a disc such as reading
and writing data.
Blob storage can manage thousands
of simultaneous uploads,
massive amounts of video data,
constantly growing log files and
can be reached from anywhere
with an Internet connection.
Disk storage. Disk storage provides
disk for virtual machines,
applications,
and other services to
access and use they need,
similar to how they would
in an on-premises scenario.
Disk storage allows
data to be persistently
stored and accessed from
unattached virtual hard disks.
Disks come in many different sizes
and performance levels,
from solid-state drives to
traditional spinning hard disk drives
with varying performance abilities.
File storage. Azure files offer
fully managed file shares in
the cloud that are accessible via
the Industry Standard Server
message Block SMB protocol.
Azure files shares can
be mounted concurrently
by Cloud or on-premises
deployments of Windows,
Linux, or MacOS. Archive storage.
Archive storage provides
a storage facility
for data that is rarely accessed.
It allows you to archive
legacy data at low cost,
to what would
traditionally have costed,
to create and maintain archives.
It is stored offline and offers
the lowest storage costs.
However, it is also
the highest access cost,
hence it is suited for archival data
that is rarely accessed.