>> Microsoft offers previews
of Azure features for
evaluation purposes.
With Azure previews, you can
test pre-release features,
products and services.
Azure previews are available
under certain terms and
conditions that are specific to
each particular Azure preview.
All preview specific terms and
conditions supplement
your existing service agreement,
which governs your use of Azure.
Some previews are not
covered by customer support.
There are different
preview categories.
Private preview means that
an Azure feature is made
available to certain Azure
customers for evaluation purposes.
Public preview means that
an Azure feature is available
publicly to all Azure customers
for evaluation purposes.
You can access preview
features by going to
the Azure Preview page
on
azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/preview.
To preview a feature, select
the "Try It" button for
the applicable feature.
You can access preview
features that are
specific to the Azure portal from
the portal preview features
page, preview.portal.azure.com.
Typical part of preview
features provide
performance navigation on
accessibility improvements
to the Azure part in interface.
Azure customers can
provide feedback in
the portal preview features they've
tested by sending
a smile in the portal,
or posting ideas and suggestions
on the Azure Portal feedback forum.
You can revert back to
the default Azure portal by going
to the standard portal page,
at portal.azure.com.
Once a feature is evaluated
and tested successfully,
it may be released to customers
as part of Azure's product,
service, or feature set.
In other words, a feature maybe made
generally available for
all Azure customers.
To get the latest updates,
via Azure products,
services, and features,
as well as product roadmaps
and announcements,
go to the Azure updates page at
azure.microsoft.com work updates.
From the Azure updates page,
you can view details
with all Azure updates.
See which updates are in
general availability,
preview or development.
Browse updates by
product category or update
type, search for updates,
subscribe to get Azure update
notifications via RSS,
and access to Microsoft
Connect page to read
Azure product news and announcements.