>> Availability Zones
are physically separate
locations within an Azure region.
Each Availability Zone is made up of
one or more data centers
equipped with
independent power,
cooling, and networking.
It is set up to be
an isolation boundary.
If one Availability Zone goes down,
the owner continues working.
The Availability Zones are typically
connected to each other to very fast,
private fiber optic networks.
Availability Zones allow
customers to run mission
critical applications
with high availability
and low latency replication.
An Availability Zones are offered
as a service within Azure.
To ensure resiliency,
there's a minimum of
three separate zones in
all enabled regions.
To achieve comprehensive
business continuity on Azure,
build your application architecture
using the combination of
Availability Zones with
Azure Region Pairs.
Regions that support
Availability Zones are listed
here: The Azure services
that support Availability Zones
are listed here.