>> Using Azure, requires
an Azure subscription,
which provides you with authenticated
and authorized access to
Azure products and services and
allows you to provision
Azure resources.
An Azure subscription
is a logical unit of
Azure services that links you
to an Azure account which is
on identity and Azure
Active Directory Azure ID
or in a directory that
an Azure ID trust.
Azure offers free and paid
subscription options,
to suit different needs
and requirements.
An account can have one or
more subscriptions with
different billing models and
access management policies
applied to each subscription.
You can use Azure subscriptions
to define boundaries
around Azure products,
services, and resources.
There are two types of subscription
boundaries that you can use.
A Billing boundary:
This subscription type
determines how Azure account
is billed for using Azure.
You can create multiple subscriptions
for different types of
billing requirements.
Access control boundary.
Azure would apply
access management policies
at the subscription level and you
can create separate subscriptions to
reflect different
organizational structures.
You can select from a range of
Azure subscription options including
A free account: This subscription is
for 30 days and
includes a $200 credit.
Pay As You Go: This subscription
allows you to pay for what you
use by attaching your credit card
or a debit card to your account.
Member offers:
Your existing membership
to certain Microsoft products and
services affords you credits for
your Azure account on
reduced rates on Azure services.
Azure Management groups are
containers for managing access,
policies, and compliance across
multiple Azure subscriptions.
Management Groups allow you to order
your Azure resources hierarchically
into collections which provides
a further level of classification
beyond subscriptions.
You can manage your Azure
subscriptions more effectively by
using Azure policy and Azure
role-based access controls.
These provide distinct
governance conditions
that you can apply to
each management group.
The resources and subscriptions
you assigned to a management group,
automatically inherit the conditions
that you apply to
that management group.