>> Azure Firewall is a managed
cloud-based network security service
that protects your Azure
virtual network resources.
You can essentially create, enforce,
and log application and
network connectivity policies
across subscriptions
and virtual networks.
Azure Firewall includes many features
including; Built-in
high availability,
Unrestricted cloud scalability,
Inbound and Outbound filtering rules,
and Azure Monitor logging.
Distributed denial of
service attacks attempt to
overwhelm on exhausted
applications resources,
making the application slow or
unresponsive to legitimate users.
DDoS attacks can be targeted at
any endpoint that is publicly
reachable through the internet.
DDoS results exposed to
the internet such as a website,
is at risk of being attacked
by a denial of service attack.
When you combine
Azure DDoS Protection
with application design
best practices,
you help provide defense
against DDoS attacks.
DDoS Protection leverages
the scale and elasticity of
Microsoft's global network to bring
DDoS mitigation capacity
to every Azure region.
Network Security Groups allow
you to filter network traffic
to and from Azure resources
in an Azure virtual network.
An NSG can contain multiple inbound
and outbound security rules,
that enabled it to filter
traffic to and from resources by
source and destination IP
Address, port, and protocol.
When you create a Nertwork
Security Group,
Azure creates a series of
default rules to provide
a baseline level of security.
You cannot remove the default rules,
which you can't override them,
by creating new rules
but higher priorities.
When choosing an Azure
network security solution,
it's not enough to simply focus
on security within perimeter,
or our network security between
services inside a network.
A layered approach provides
multiple levels of protection,
so that if an attacker
gets through one layer,
there are fraud protections in place.
A common security concept
that is applied
to computing systems
is Defense in Depth,
which is essentially a layered
approach to providing security.
Perimeter Layer. The Network
Perimeter Layers about
protecting organizations from
network-based attacks
against your resources.
Identifying these
attacks, alerting and
eliminating their impact is important
to keep your network secure.
To do this, you can use Azure
DDoS Protection to filter
large-scale attacks
before they can cause
denial of service for end-users.
Use perimeter firewalls
with Azure Firewall to
identify and alert on a malicious
attacks against your network.
The Networking Layer, at
this layer to focuses on limiting
network connectivity
across all your resources
to only allow what is required.
As best practices, you should,
limit communication
between resources through
segmenting your network and
configuring access controls.
Deny be Default, restrict
inbound internet access
intimate outbound where appropriate.
Implement secure connectivity
to on-premises networks.
Combining services.
You can also combine
multiple Azure networking and
security services to manage
your network security and provide
increased layered protection.
You can combine Network Security
Groups and Azure Firewall.
Azure Firewall compliments Network
Security Group functionality,
together they provide better defense
in depth and network security.
You can combine Application Gateway
WebApplication Firewall
and Azure Firewall.
Web Application Firewall is
a feature of application gateway,
that provides centralized
inbound protection
of your web applications,
from common exploits
and vulnerabilities.
As computing environments move from
customer controlled data centers
to cloud datacenters,
the responsibility for
security also shifts.
Security is now a concern shared by
both the cloud provider
and the customers.