>> Now, working on Azure
allows you to connect
cloud and on-premises
infrastructure and
services to provide
your customers and users with
the best possible experience.
Once your resources moved to Azure,
they require the same
networking functionality
as an on-premises deployment.
Some of the most common
networking service types in
Azure, Azure Virtual Network.
Azure Virtual Network enables
many types of Azure resources such as
Azure VMs to securely
communicate with
each other the internet
and on-premises networks.
With Azure Virtual Network,
you can provide
isolation, segmentation,
communication when on-premises
and cloud resources,
routing and filtering
of networking traffic.
Azure Load Balancer.
Azure Load Balancer can provide
scale for applications and create
high availability for your services.
You can use load balancer with
incoming internet traffic,
internal traffic
across Azure services,
port forwarding for
specific traffic or
outbound connectivity for
VMs in your virtual network.
VPN gateway. A VPN gateway can
also be referred to as a Virtual
Network Gateway that is used to send
encrypted traffic between
an Azure Virtual Network
and an on-premises location
over the public internet.
Provides a more secure
connection from
on-premises to Azure
over the Internet.
Azure Application Gateway.
Azure Application Gateway is
a web traffic load balancer
that enables you to manage
traffic to your web applications,
and it's a connection
through its users
connect to your application.
Content Delivery Network.
A Content Delivery Network
is a distributed network of
servers that can efficiently
deliver web content to users.
It is a way to get
content to users in
their local region
to minimize latency.