>> Azure Marketplace is
a service on Azure that
helps connect end-users
with Microsoft partners,
independent software vendors,
and startups that are offering
their solutions and services which
are optimized to run on Azure.
Azure Marketplace allows customers,
mostly IT professionals and
cloud developers, to find, try,
purchase, and provision applications
and services from hundreds of
leading service providers all
certified to run an Azure.
This solution catalog spans several
industry categories including,
but not limited to,
open-source container platforms,
virtual machine images, databases,
application build and
deployment software,
developer tools, track detection,
blockchain, and many more.
Using Azure Marketplace, you can
provision end-to-end solutions
quickly and reliably hosted in
your own Azure environment.
At the time of recording, this
includes over 8,000 listings.