>> Azure Service Health is a suite
of experiences that provide
personalized guidance and support
when issues with Azure
services effect through.
It can notify you, help you
understand the impact of issues,
keep you updated as
the issue is resolved.
Azure Service Health can
also help you prepare
for planned maintenance,
and changes that could affect
the availability of your resources.
Azure Service Health is
composed of Azure status.
Azure status provides
a global view of
the health status of Azure services.
With Azure status, you can get
up to the minute information on
service availability. Service health.
Service health provides you with
a customizable dashboard that
tracks the state of
your Azure services
in the regions where you use them.
In this dashboard, you can track
active events such as
ongoing service issues,
upcoming planned maintenance or
relevant health advisories.
Azure Resource Health.
Resource Health helps you
diagnose and obtain support,
when an Azure service issue
affects your resources.
Provides your details about
the current and past state
of your resources
and also provides technical support
to help you mitigate problems.
Together, these experiences
provides you with
a comprehensive view into the health
of Azure at the granularity,
that is most relevant to you.