>> Welcome to the course,
Microsoft Azure Fundamentals.
This course will provide
foundational level knowledge
of cloud services
and how those services are
provided with Microsoft Azure.
The course can be taken
as an optional first step
and learning about cloud
services and Microsoft Azure.
The course will cover
general cloud computing concepts as
well as general cloud
computing models
and services such as public,
private, an hybrid clouds,
an infrastructure, platform,
and software as a service.
It will also cover some core
Azure services and solutions,
such as compute, networking,
storage and others,
and solutions such as Internet of
Things, artificial intelligence,
and data analytics as well as
key Azure pillar services
concerning security,
privacy, compliance and trust.
It will finally cover
pricing and support
services that are available
with Microsoft Azure.
There are no prescribed Hands
on components to the course.
There are no labs, but we
would encourage you to sign
up for a free Microsoft
Azure account on
azure.microsoft.com/free
and to identify
and try out somebody areas as they're
discussed during the course
if you have time.
Thank you for signing up
and taking this course.
We hope it is of some benefit
to you and that you enjoy.