>> Now working on Azure
allows you to connect
Cloud and on-premises
infrastructure and
services to provide
your customers and users with
the best possible experience.
Once your resources move to Azure,
they require the same
networking functionality
as an on-premises deployment.
Some of the most common networking
service types in Azure are:
Azure Virtual Network:
Azure Virtual Network
enables many types
of Azure resources,
such as Azure VMs,
to securely communicate
with each other,
the internet and
on-premises networks.
With Azure Virtual Network, you
can provide isolation, segmentation,
communication when on-premises
and cloud resources,
routing, and filtering
of networking traffic.
Azure Load Balancer: Azure Load
Balancer can provide scale
for applications and create
high availability for your services.
You can use load balance with
incoming internet traffic,
internal traffic
across Azure services,
port forwarding for specific traffic,
or outbound connectivity for
VMs in your virtual network.
VPN gateway: A VPN Gateway
can also be referred to as
a Virtual Network Gateway.
But a VPN Gateway is
a specific type of
virtual network gateway
that is used to send
encrypted traffic between
an Azure Virtual Network
on an on-premises location
over the public internet.
It provides a more secure connection
from on-premises to
Azure over the internet.
Azure Application Gateway:
Azure Application Gateway is
a web traffic load balancer
that enables you
to manage traffic to
your web applications.
It's the connection
through which users
connect to your application.
Content Delivery Network:
A Content Delivery Network
is a distributed network of
servers that can efficiently,
deliver web content to users.
It is a way to get
content to users in
their local region
to minimize latency.