>> So, what are some of
the advantages and disadvantages
as you compare the different
types of cloud model?
Now for Public Cloud, some advantages
are: no capital expenditure.
You don't have to buy a new server
up and running north to scale.
Agility, Applications can
be up and running and
accessible very quickly and deep
provisioned whenever needed.
Consumption-based model,
pay only for what you
use and it operates under
an operational expenditure model.
Maintenance, there
is no responsibility
for maintenance or updates
for any of the hardware.
Skills, there's no
deep technical skills
needed to be able to deploy,
use and gain the benefits
of Public Cloud.
You can leverage the skills
and expertise of
the Cloud provider to ensure
your workloads are secure,
safe, and made highly
available in full part of.
Some disadvantages down for
Public Cloud are: Security,
it maybe specific security
requirements that cannot be met by
using Public Clouds depending on
your industry or your workload.
Compliance, that maybe
government policies,
industry standards or
legal requirements with
Public Clouds can not meet.
Ownership, you don't own
the hardware services,
you can not manage them as you wish.
Specific scenarios, if you
have a specific scenario,
unique business requirements
such as having to maintain
a legacy application that may be
difficult to meet that requirement
with Public Cloud.
Let's move on and take a look at
some of the advantages
for Private Cloud.
Control, you have total control over
the resources and can configure
them anyway you wish.
Security, you have
total control over security.
Compliance, if you have
very strict security compliance
or legal requirements,
Private Cloud maybe the
only viable option.
Specific scenarios, if you have
a specific scenario and not supported
mainly by Public Cloud provider,
such as having to maintain
a legacy application,
it may be a preferable scenario
to run your application
locally and have
total control over it.
Some disadvantages of Private Cloud
are: Upfront capital expenditure,
you need to purchase the hardware
for startup and maintenance.
Agility, not as agile
as Public Cloud,
as you need to purchase and setup
all the underlying infrastructure
before you can leverage them.
Maintenance, you have responsibility
for the maintenance and
updates of the hardware.
Skills, it requires IT skills and
expertise that may be
hard or costly to access.
Find the, let's take a look at
the advantages for Hybrid Cloud.
Flexibility and agility,
most flexible and agile
scenario allowing for
decisions through on
either locally in
Private Cloud or in Public Cloud
depending on your need.
Costs, can take advantage of
economies of scale that
comes with Public Cloud.
Control, you can still
maintain total control over
application on data if
you need by using
your Private Cloud option.
Security, you can have
total control over security
in your Private Cloud.
Compliance, maintain
the ability to support
very strict security, compliance
or legal requirements if needed.
Specific scenarios, you can
maintain the ability to support
specific scenarios not supported
easily by a public cloud provider,
such as running legacy applications.
In this case, you could keep
an old system running
locally and connect it to
the public cloud for authorization
or storage or you could host
a website into Public Cloud
and link it to
a highly secure database hosted in
your Private Cloud for example.
There are so many disadvantages
for Hybrid Cloud.
Upfront capital expenditure.
Upfront CapEX is still
required before you can
leverage your Private Cloud.
Costs, wanting
two deployment models can be
more expensive than selecting
one deployment model.
Skills, deep technical skills are
still required to be able
to set up a Private Cloud.
Ease of management, you
need to make sure there are
clear guidelines to avoid any
confusion, complications, or misuse.