>> Azure Security Center is
a monitoring service that provides
threat protection across all of
your services both in
Azure and on-premises.
Security center can provide
security recommendations based on
your configurations,
resources and networks.
Monitor security settings
across on-premises and
cloud workloads and
automatically apply
required security to new
services as they come online.
Continuously monitor all your
services and perform
automatic security
assessments to identify
potential vulnerabilities
before they can be exploited.
Use Machine learning to
detect and block malware
from being installed on
your virtual machines and services.
Analyze and identify
potential inbound attacks,
and help to investigate threats and
any post reach activity
that might have occurred.
Provide just-in-time
access control for ports,
reducing your attack
surface by ensuring
the network only allows
traffic that you require.
You can integrate
security center into
your workflows and
use it in many ways.
Here are two examples; Firstly,
use security center for
an incident response.
Many organizations
learn how to respond to
security incidents only
after suffering an attack.
To reduce costs and damage
it's important to have
an incident response plan in place
before an attack takes place.
You can use Azure security center in
different stages of
an instant response.
You can use security
center during to detect,
assess, and diagnose stages.
Detect: Review the first indication
of an event investigation.
Use security center
dashboard to review
the initial verification that
a high priority security
alert was raised.
Assess: Perform
the initial assessment
to obtain more information
about the suspicious activity.
Obtain more information
about the security alert.
Diagnose: Conduct
a technical investigation
and identify containment, mitigation
and workaround strategies.
You can follow the remediation
steps described by
security center in
that particular security alert.
The second example, use
security center recommendations
to enhance security.
You can reduce the chances of
a significant security event
by configuring
a security policy and
then implementing
the recommendations provided
by Azure security center.
A security policy defines
a set of controls that are
recommended for resources but did
not specify subscription
or resource group.
In security center
you define policies
according to your company's
security requirements.
Security center analyzes
the security state of
your Azure resources,
when security center identifies
potential security vulnerabilities,
it creates recommendations based on
the control set into security policy.
The recommendations guide
you to the process of
configuring the needed
security controls.