>> So, let's go and create
an Azure free account.
We launch a browser
session with Edge,
it's in private session to make sure
it doesn't sign in
with another account,
we want this to be a new account.
We go to azure.microsoft.com.
This will bring us to the homepage
for Azure and you can see
there's an option here to go
to their free account section.
Or if we scroll down,
we have another option here to
sign up for a free account.
We click on that "Create
your free account"
and that brings us to
azure.microsoft.com free
under create your free
account today page.
Before we go ahead and
create the account,
we just scroll down to
see some more details
around the Azure free account.
We can see the free account,
we got 12 months services
$200 free credit over 30 days
and there are some services
which are always free.
If you continue to scroll down,
you'll see some more details around
what products are free for 12 months.
There's Windows and Linux
virtual machines, disk storage,
some database services and
if we keep going down,
we'll see some details around
more products that are always free.
Active Directory,
Functions, Up services.
Then we also have a section
which provides us with
some more details and ask us
if we have to pay anything,
no and there's no charge
with the free account.
You're not charged anything for it.
What happens after you use
your $200 free credit or
your 30 days are over.
You can upgrade to a pay-as-you-go
subscription to get continued access.
What happens at the end of
the 12 months free products.
Again, you can upgrade
to a pay-as-you-go
subscription and what
do I need to sign up?
You need a phone number, credit card,
debit card, and
a Microsoft account username.
If you click on the FAQ.
there's more answers in here
around questions for
the free account.
You can scroll through
and have a look
at some of them if you need.
So we return to the free account
page and click "Start free".
We get prompted to sign in with
a Microsoft account details.
If we don't have one,
we can create one here
clicking on the "Create one
link" and following the prompts,
otherwise, enter your details.
Fill in the details as
you're prompted here.
You log in a valid phone
number and connect the
multi-factor authentication
requiring you to enter a code or
receive and enter a code.
Enter your preferences as you go.
You need to enter your credit
or debit card number,
you have to check
the checkbox to agree
to the terms and conditions
and then click "Sign up"
and that was successful
and we're ready to go.
If we click on "Go to the portal",
that brings us to the Azure portal,
with a new account and
your all new Azure subscription.
We get prompted
how much credit we have left.
We get prompted to start a tour.
Which we can do and follow around.
We click on "Home" and
you can click around
some services and see
we're ready to go.