>> When we are talking
about big data,
we're referring to
large volumes of data.
Data from weather systems,
communication systems,
imaging platforms, and
many other scenarios
generate large amounts of data.
This amount of data
becomes increasingly
hard to make sense of and
make decisions around.
The volumes are so large that
traditional data forms of
processing and analysis
are no longer appropriate.
Microsoft Azure supports
a broad range of technologies and
services to provide Big Data
and analytic solutions.
So the most common big data
and analytics service types in
Azure are: Azure SQL Data Warehouse.
Azure SQL Data Warehouse is
a cloud-based enterprise data
warehouse that leverages
massively parallel
processing (MPP) to run
complex queries quickly
across petabytes of data.
Once data is stored in
SQL Data Warehouse,
you can run analytics
on massive scale.
Compared to traditional
database systems,
analysis queries finish in
seconds instead of minutes,
or hours instead of days.
Azure HDInsight.
Azure HDInsight is
a fully managed open-source
analytic service for enterprises.
It is a cloud service that
makes it easier, faster,
and more cost effective to
process massive amounts of data.
HDInsights allow you to run
popular open-source
frameworks and create
cluster types such as Apache Spark,
Apache Hadoop, Apache Kafka,
Apache HBase, Apache Storm,
and Machine Learning service.
Azure Data Lake analytics.
Azure Data Lake Analytics is
an on-demand analytics job service
that simplifies big data.
Instead of deploying,
configuring, and tuning hardware,
you write queries to transform
your data and extract
valuable insights.
The analytic service can
handle jobs of any scale
instantly by setting the dial
for how much power unit.
You only pay for your job
when it is running,
making it more cost-effective