>> Every Azure subscription
includes free access to
the following basic support services:
Billing and subscription support,
Azure products and
services documentation,
online self-help
documentation, white papers,
and community support forums.
Microsoft offers four paid
Azure support plans
for customers who require
technical and operational support.
Providing different Azure
support options allows
customers to choose a plan
that best fits their needs.
Available to support
plans are, developer.
Developer support is appropriate
for Azure use in trial and
non-production
environments and includes
business areas access to
support engineers via email,
less than eight business hours
for initial response time.
Standards support is appropriate for
Azure use in production
environments and
includes access to support engineers
via email and phone, 24-7.
Critical business impacts
incident submission and
less than one hour initial response
time for severity A accidents.
Professional direct
is appropriate for
organizations with business-critical
dependence on Azure.
This option includes all features
of the standard option as well
as escalation management
for priority issues,
proactive guidance from a team of
professional direct delivery
managers, onboarding services,
service reviews, and
Azure Advisor consultations,
architectural guidance
based on best practices.
Premier. This is ideal
for organizations with
substantial dependence on
Microsoft products including Azure.
Dissolution includes
all the features of
professional direct as
well as support assistance
for all Microsoft products
and services,
less than 15 minutes
initial response time with
Azure Rapid Response.
Service reviews and
reporting delivered by
a designated Technical
Account Manager.
Customers specific architect would
support such as design reviews,
performance tuning,
and configuration.
The support plans you can
select and how you are
billed for support
depends on the type of
Azure customer you are
and the type of
Azure subscription you have.
For example, developer support
is not available to
enterprise customers.
Enterprise customers can purchase
Standard, Professional Direct,
and Premier Support
plans and be billed for
support as part of
their enterprise agreement.
Conversely, if your purchase is
support plan when a
pay-as-you-go subscription,
your support plan is charged to
your monthly Azure subscription bill.