>> There are three main
customer types on which
there are available
purchasing options for Azure
products and services contingent.
Enterprise: Enterprise customers sign
an enterprise agreement with Azure,
that commits them to spending
a negotiated amount
on Azure services,
which they typically pay annually.
Enterprise customers also have
access to customized Azure pricing.
Web direct: Web direct customers
sign up for Azure, through
the Azure website.
Web direct customers pay
the same prices that the
general public pay
for Azure resources,
and their monthly billing and
payments occur through
the Azure website.
Cloud Service Provider:
Cloud Service Providers, CSPs,
typically are Microsoft
partner companies that
a customer hires to bill
solutions on top of Azure.
Payment and billing for Azure usage
occurs through the Customer CSP.
Products and services in Azure
are arranged by category,
which have various resources
that you can provision.
You select the Azure products and
services that fit your requirements,
and your account is billed according
to the Azure consumption-based model.
When you provision an Azure resource,
Azure creates one or more meter
instances for that resource.
The meters track the resources usage,
and each meter generates
a usage record that is used
to calculate your bill.
For example, a single virtual
machine that you provision in Azure,
might have some of
the following meters tracking
its usage: Compute hours,
IP address hours, data transfer in,
data transfer out, and others.
An Azure free account provide
subscribers with a $200 Azure credit,
that they can use for Azure
paid products during
a 30-day trial period.
Once you use that $200 credit
or reach your trials end,
Azure suspends your account unless
you sign up for a paid account.