>> Azure Policy is a service in
Azure that you use to create,
assign, and manage policies.
These policies enforce
different rules
and effects over your resources.
So, those resources stay
compliant which are
corporate standards and
service-level agreements.
Azure Policy does this by using
policies and initiatives.
The journey of creating and
implementing a policy in
Azure Policy begins with
creating a policy definition.
Every policy definition has
conditions under which is enforced.
It has an accompanying effect that
takes place if
the conditions are met.
The process of applying
a policy to your
resources consist of
the following steps.
Firstly, create a policy definition.
Secondly, assign a definition
to a scope of resources.
Thirdly, view
policy evaluation results.
Examples of policy
definitions would include,
Allowed Storage Account SKUs.
To this policy definition
has a set of conditions and
rules that the term
better storage account,
that is being applied is
within a set of SKU sizes.
It's effect is to deny
all storage accounts that
do not adhere to the set
of defined SKU sizes.
Allowed Resource Types.
This policy definition
has a set of conditions
and rules to specify
the resource types,
that your organization can apply.
Its effect is to deny
all resources that are not
part of this defined list.
Allowed Locations. This policy
enable you to restrict
the location such organizations could
specify when deploying resources.
Its effect is used to enforce
your geographic
compliance requirements.
Allowed Virtual Machines SKUs.
This policy enables you to
specify a set of VM SKUs,
that your organization can apply.
Initiatives work alongside
policies in Azure Policy.
An initiative definition is
a set of policy definitions
that help track your compliance
state for larger goal.
Even if you have a single policy,
we recommend using initiatives if you
anticipate increasing the number
of policies over time.
Like a policy assignment,
an initiative assignment is
an initiative definition
assigned to a specific scope.
Initiative assignments
reduce the need to
make several initiative
definitions for each scope.
This scope could also range from
managing group, to a resource group.
Initiatives can be assigned
just as policies can.
Role-based access control provides
fine-grained access management
for Azure resources,
enabling you to grant users only
the rights they need
to perform their jobs.
RBAC is provided at no additional
cost to all Azure subscribers.
Examples of when you
might use RBAC include,
when you want to allow a user to
manage VMs in a subscription.
I'm not a user to manage
virtual networks.
Allow a database
administrator group to
manage SQL databases
in a subscription.
Allow user to manage all resources in
resource groups such as
VMs, websites, and subnets.
Allow an application to access
all resources in a resource group.
To view access permissions,
access the access control,
the IAM blade in the Azure portal.
On this blade, you can see who has
access to an area under a role.
Using the same blade,
you can grant or remove access.
Locks help you prevent
accidental deletion
or modification of
your Azure resources.
You can manage these locks
from it in the Azure portal.
To view out or delete locks,
go to the settings section of
Azure resources, Settings Blade.
You may need to lock
a subscription, resource group,
or resource to prevent other users
in your organization from
accidentally deleting or
modifying critical resources.
You can set the lock level to
"CanNotDelete" or "ReadOnly".
CanNotDelete, means authorized users
can still read and modify resource,
but they can't delete the resource.
ReadOnly means authorized users
can read a resource,
but they can't delete
or update the resource.
In the Azure portal,
the locks are called
"Delete" and "Read-only"
respectively.
As discussed earlier in the course,
I should advise you as
a free service built into
Azure that provides recommendations
on high availability,
security performance, and cost.
Advisor analyzes
your deployed services,
and looks for ways to improve
your environment across
these four areas.
Azure Advisor provides
security recommendations,
by integrating
the Azure Security Center.
You can view the security
center recommendations
on the Security tab of
the Advisor dashboard.
You can then click deeper into
the Security Center Recommendations.
Azure Blueprint is a declarative way
to orchestrate deployment
of various resource templates
and other artifacts.
But Azure Blueprint, the relationship
between the blueprint definition,
what should be deployed,
and the blueprint assignment,
what was deployed is preserved.
Disconnection supports
improved deployment tracking
and auditing. Usage scenario.
Adhering to security or
compliance requirements whether
government or industry can be
difficult and time consuming.
To help you at
auditing, traceability,
and compliance with your deployments,
use Azure Blueprint
artifacts and tools.
Time-consuming paperwork is no longer
needed and your part to
certification is expedited.
Note that the time of
writing this course,
Azure Blueprint is in preview and
has not been released generally.