>> The pricing calculator tool
helps you estimate the cost of
Azure products and organizes
Azure products into categories,
and you choose the
Azure products you need
and configured them according
to your specific requirements.
Azure then provides
a detailed estimate of
the costs associated with
your selections and configurations.
The pricing calculator
provides estimates,
not actual price quotes.
Actual prices may vary depending
on the date of purchase,
the payment currency you are using,
your type of Azure customer you are.
Getting new estimates from
the pricing calculator by adding,
removing, or reconfiguring
your selected products.
You can also access pricing details,
product details, and documentation
for each product from
the pricing calculator.
The options that you can configure in
the pricing calculator vary
between products,
but basic configuration options
include: region,
tier, billing options, support
options, programs, and offers.
The total cost of
ownership calculator,
is a tool that you use to estimate
cost savings you can realize
by migrating to Azure.
To use the TCO Calculator,
you need to define your workloads.
Enter details about
your on-premise infrastructure
into the TCO Calculator.
Adjust assumptions: adjust the values
of key assumptions that
the TCO calculator makes,
which might vary between customers.
View the report:
The TCO Calculator generates
a detailed report based on
the details you enter and
the adjustments you make.
The report allows you to compare
the cost of your on-premises
infrastructure with
the costs of using Azure products and
services to host your
infrastructure in the Cloud.