>> Azure Advisor is
a free service built into Azure
that provides recommendations
on high availability,
security, performance, and cost.
Advisor analyzes your deployed
services and looks for
ways to improve your environment
across those four areas.
With Azure Advisor, you can
get proactive, actionable,
and personalized best practices and
recommendations,
improved performance, security,
and high availability
of your resources,
and identify opportunities to
reduce your overall Azure costs,
and get recommendations with
proposed actions inline.
You can access Azure Advisor
through the Azure portal.
After you sign into the portal,
auto select "Advisor" from
the "Navigation" menu or search
for it in the "All Services" menu.
You can download recommendations
from Azure Advisor in
PDF or CSV format, which
you can then share.