>> So, let's go ahead and
create some blob storage.
So, we're logged in
to the Azure portal,
a portal.azure.com.
Run the "Home" page.
We get down the list of
services on the left.
We look for "Storage Accounts",
and into "Storage Accounts" pane,
we click "Create Storage Account".
With the series of tabs you need to
configure into "Create
Storage Account" pane.
Subscription is free trial.
We create a new "Resource Group",
we call it blobrg1.
We need a storage account name,
and it needs to be
a unique name across Azure.
If you append your initials or
something like that to the name,
that may help to make it unique.
Blobstrek03, we'll take
the default location,
"Standard" performance, and for
"Account kind'' we'll
select "BlobStorage".
Take the defaults, let it complete
the validation which
will run successfully,
and then click ''Create''.
That deployment has succeeded.
We'll go to a ''Resource Group'',
open our storage account.
Let's scroll down to "Blob
Service" and then "Blobs".
Next, we need to create a
container when in blob storage.
We've got a blob container.
For public access level,
we'll select ''Anonymous Read
Access for Containers and Blobs''.
Click ''OK''. So, if we
open up blob container now,
you want to upload some files
to it, click ''Upload''.
Browse some file startup,
click ''Upload''.
We can see the file we uploaded at
blob storage is available here.
Click on the ''... ''.
We can open up an access to
content in the blob file.
If you go to ''Blob Properties'',
copy the "URL", drop
it into a browser.
So, that blob storage content
is now available
globally via that URL.