>> When selecting your cloud
provider to host your solutions,
you should understand
how the provider can
help you comply with
regulations and standards.
Some questions to ask about
a potential provider include,
how compliant is the cloud provider
when it comes to
handling sensitive data?
How compliant is the services
offered by the cloud provider?
How can I deploy
my own cloud-based solutions to
scenarios that have accreditation
or compliance requirements?
Microsoft invests heavily
in the development of
robust and innovative
compliance processes.
Microsoft provides
the most comprehensive set
of compliance offerings,
including certifications
and attestations,
of any cloud service provider.
Well, the following list is not
a full list of compliance offerings,
it will provide you with
an idea of the level of
compliance offerings that
are available within Azure.