>> Artificial intelligence, in
the context of cloud computing,
is based around the broad range of
services the core of which
is machine learning.
Machine learning is a
data science technique
that allows computers to use
existing data to forecast future
behaviors, outcomes, and trends.
Using machine learning, computers
learn without being
explicitly programmed.
Forecasts or predictions for
machine learning can make
apps and devices smarter.
For example, when you shop online,
machine learning helps
recommend other products
you might like based on
what you've purchased.
Or when your credit card is swiped,
machine learning compares
the transaction to
a database of transactions
and helps detect fraud.
When your robot vacuum cleaner
vacuums the room,
machine learning helps to
decide whether the job is done.
Some of the most common artificial
intelligence and machine
learning service types in Azure are,
Azure Machine Learning Service,
Azure Machine Learning
Service provides
a cloud-based environment you
can use to develop, train,
test, deploy, manage, and
track machine learning models.
It fully supports open source
technologies so you can use
tens of thousands of
open source Python packages
with machine learning components.
Azure Machine Learning Service can
auto-generate a model
on auto-tune for you.
It'll let you start training on
your local machine and then
you can scale up to the Cloud.
Azure Machine Learning Studio,
Azure Machine Learning Studio
is a collaborative drag
and drop visual work space
where you can build,
test and deploy
machine learning solutions
without needing to write code.
It uses pre-built and pre-configured
machine learning algorithms
on data handling modules.
Use Machine Learning Studio
when you want to
experiment with machine
learning models quickly and easily.