>> Azure Key Vault is
a centralized cloud service
for storing application secrets.
Key Vault helps you control
your application secrets by keeping
them in a single central location
and providing secure access,
permission control,
and access logging.
Usage scenarios include:
Secrets management.
You can use Key Vault to securely
store and tightly control
access to tokens,
passwords, certificates,
API Keys and other secrets.
Key management: You also
can use Key Vault as
a management solution.
Key Vault makes it easier
to create and control
the encryption keys used
to encrypt your data.
Certificate management: Key Vault is
a service that lets you
more easily provision,
manage and deploy
public and private certificates
for use with Azure on
your internal connected resources.
We store secrets backed by
hardware security modules.
The secrets and keys
can be protected by
software or hardware
security modules.
Microsoft Azure
Information Protection
is a cloud-based solution that helps
organizations classify and optionally
protects documents and
emails by applying labels.
Labels can be applied
automatically by administrators to
define rules and conditions
or manually by users,
or a combination of both whereby
users are given recommendations.
After your content is classified
and optionally protected,
you can then track and control
how the content is used.
Azure Advanced Threat
Protection, Azure ATP,
is a cloud-based security
solution that identifies,
detects and helps you
investigate advanced threats,
compromise identities and
malicious insider actions
directed at your organization.
Azure ATP is capable of detecting
known malicious attacks
and techniques,
security issues, and risks
against your network.
Azure ATP consists of the following
components: The Azure ATP
portal: Azure ATP has
its own portal to which you
monitor and respond to
suspicious activity.
As portal.atp.azure.com.
Azure ATP sensor: Azure ATP sensors
are installed directly on
your domain controllers.
The sensors that monitor
domain controller traffic without
requiring a dedicated server
or configuring port mirroring,
and Azure ATP Cloud Service.
Azure ATP cloud service runs
on Azure infrastructure
and is connected to Microsoft's
Intelligent Security Graph.