>> Azure Monitor maximize
the availability and performance of
your applications by delivering
a comprehensive solution
for collecting,
analyzing, and acting on telemetry
from your Cloud and
on-premises environments.
It helps you understand how
your applications are
performing and proactively
identifies issues affecting them
on the resources they depend on.
As soon as you create an Azure
subscription and start adding
resources such as
virtual machines and web apps,
Azure Monitor starts collecting data.
Activity Logs record when
resources are created or modified,
and Metrics tell you how
the resource is performing,
and the resources
that it's consuming.
You can extend the data
you're collecting into
the actual operation
of the resources by
enabling diagnostics and adding
an agent to compute resources.
Under the Resource Settings,
you can enable diagnostics,
and you can enable
guest-level monitoring,
collect performance data
using performance counters,
enable various Event Logs,
enable or disable Crash Dumps,
send your diagnostic data to
other services for
more analysis using Sinks,
and configure your Agent Settings