>> People are able to access more
information than ever before.
It began at a personal
digital assistants,
PDAs then more often to smartphones.
Now there are smart watches,
smart thermostat and
even smart refrigerators.
Personal computers used to the norm.
Now the internet
allows any item that's
online capable to access
valuable information.
This ability for devices to garner
and then relay information for
data analysis is referred to
as the Internet of Things.
There are a number of
services that can assist and
drive end-to-end solutions
for IoT and Azure.
Two of the Core Azure IoT services
are: IoT Central.
IoT Central is a fully
managed global IoT software
as a service solution that
makes it easy to connect,
monitor, and manage
your IoT assets at scale.
No Cloud expertise is
required to use IoT Central.
As a result, you can bring
your connected products to
market foster while staying
focused on your customers.
Azure IoT Hub, Azure IoT Hub
is a managed service hosted
in the Cloud that acts as
a central message job for
bidirectional communication
between your IoT application
and the devices it manages.
You can use Azure IoT Hub
to build IoT solutions with
reliable and secure
communications to millions of
IoT devices on a cloud
hosted solution back-end.
You can connect virtually
any device to IoT Hub.