>> So, let's go ahead and create
a Virtual Machine in Azure.
First, we log in to the portal,
portal.azure.com,
we're on the homepage.
I'm going to go down to the list
of services on the left,
locate "Virtual Machines" and then
click "Create Virtual Machine."
Then, to create
a virtual machine pane,
there's a series of tabs we
need to go through to fill in
for the configuration that you
wish to deploy and a virtual machine.
The subscription is Free Trial.
We wish to create
a new resource group,
into which we will have
all the resources placed in
a single location so we can
manage them as a single entity.
We'll name it VM1
our virtual machine name,
we'll call it virtualmachin1.
We'll take to the fourth
region of East US.
You won't configure
any availability options.
For an image, we'll go to
"Browse all images and disks".
I may look for Windows image.
We'll select Windows 10 Pro.
Accept the default disk size,
we need to put in
a username and password.
We use username azureuser.
Your password needs to meet
the minimum complexity requirements
for Azure and make sure you
take note of it as well
because we'll be using
this password to
connect to the virtual
machine after it's deployed.
For "Inbound Port Rules",
we need to allow selected ports.
This is to allow us to connect to
the virtual machine
after it's deployed,
and we'll select all
of these ports here.
We'll only be connected
over the RDP port,
but we'll enable them all here
now. You can click "Next."
Accept the defaults for
"Disks" and the defaults for
"Networking" and continue to
accepting that all the defaults,
and then Azure is going to validate
the deployment configuration.
The validation was successful,
and we click "Create".
The deployment has now started.
So, we can see all the resources
as they're being
created and we go to
the resource group.
You can do that directly
from this deployment pane.
Or we can locate "Resource Groups" on
the left-hand side and open up
the resource group we just created.
In here, we can see
all the resources that
are currently under deployment.
That has successfully deployed.
We can see all the resources
that have been deployed
with the virtual machine
itself, the disk,
the Network Interface,
the public IP address,
the Network Security Group,
the Storage Account and
the Virtual Network.
All of these resources
are required to make
that virtual machine
fully functional.
We can access to
virtual machine by opening up
the virtual machine and
clicking "Connect".
In the "Connect to a
Virtual Machine" pane,
click "Download RDP File",
and click "OK" to open.
In the RDP connection dialog,
click "Connect", enter your username
and password which is specified
when you're configuring
the virtual machine.
In our case it was azureuser.
I'm going to use dot backslash to
indicate it's a local account.
Click "Yes" to connect,
and that's now logging in
to the virtual machine.
You can see that's
a fully functioning virtual machine.
Our virtual machine is now deployed
and available to run our workloads.
Remember that running
virtual machines
are costing money
while they're running,
and you should shut down and
delete the virtual machine.
The quickest way to delete
a virtual machine will be to
delete "the resource group" and
all the resources within it.
If you're not going to
use the virtual machine,
it would be advisable to
delete a resource group now.