>> So let's log into the Azure portal
and have a look at how
we can customize it.
So we signed into the Azure Portal
by portal.azure.com.
Their default view is
onto the homepage.
Here we have a list of useful links,
categories, services that
you may want to use.
You can change your default view.
You click on settings, we
access to portal settings,
and we can choose our default view
to be either the home
or the dashboard.
We can change the color contrast,
notifications, and the language
that the UI appears,
as well as the regional formats.
So if we select to
have the dashboard as
our default view of me login
to the portal and click Apply,
the next time you
log into the portal,
the dashboard will appear
first as the default view.
If we click on dashboard, we
see we have a series of tiles.
We can customize and modify
our dashboard view by clicking Edit,
we can rearrange and
resize our tiles.
We can remove items,
drag them around,
resize them, reorder them.
We can also bring in tiles for
specific service or products
in the tile gallery.
We see for virtual machines we have
21 different tiles
available around CPU Usage,
Memory Usage, Disk Writes and more.
We can drag these and use them.
If we had an application and we
wanted to keep a close eye on it,
we could drag into
critical resources into
our dashboard and have them
display in almost real-time.
So we can see disk writes,
memory, CPU performance,
and our dashboard view.
And when we're finished,
click Done Customizing.
You can also have
multiple dashboards,
you can create a new dashboard.
Drag in some tiles,
and I can then choose
which dashboard I wish to view.
You can download and export
the dashboard as well,
and then load it as a JSON file,
and you can save that and share it.
You can also access All Services,
if you're looking for
a particular service.
That's the Advisor, type
in to All Services box,
or virtual machines,
type in a keyword
and you get all the related services
appearing which we can then chose.
Likewise, we can click
Create a Resource,
type in the object that
we're looking for,
and everything related to storage in
this instance appears in the pane.
Accessing the icons in the top right,
you can also provide feedback,
obtain help, configure a settings
as we've already seen,
view our notifications,
view our directory and
subscription detail,
and also access the Cloud Shell,
which is a browser-based
management tool.