>> Infrastructure-as-a-Service
is the most basic category
of Cloud computing services.
With IaaS, you rent
IT infrastructure servers,
and virtual machines,
storage networks,
operating systems from
a Cloud provider on a pay
for what you use basis.
It is an instant
computing infrastructure,
provisioned and managed over
secure Internet connection.
Using a virtual machine servers,
to run an operating system in
the cloud will be an example of IaaS.
Platform-as-a-Service, provides
an environment for building,
testing, and deploying
software applications.
The goal of PaaS, is to help
you create an application
as quickly as
possible without having to worry
about managing the
underlying infrastructure.
For example, when deploying
a Web application using PaaS,
you don't have to install
an operating system,
Web server, or even system updates.
It's a complete development
and deployment environment
into Cloud with resources that enable
you to deliver everything
from simple Cloud-based apps
to sophisticated Cloud enabled
enterprise applications.
Resources are purchased from
a Cloud service provider
in a pay for what
you use basis and accessed over
secure Internet connection.
Running a website and a platform such
as Azure Web Apps would
be an example of PaaS.
Software-as-a-Service,
is software that
is essentially hosted and
managed for customers.
It allows users to connect to and
use Cloud-based apps
over the Internet.
How many examples are
email, calendaring,
Office tools, such as
Microsoft Office 365.
It is typically licensed to a
monthly or an annual subscription.